Guide to the Samuel P. Hays Post-World War II Radical Movements Publications Collection, 1915-1982 AIS.1981.18
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Organizations and Individuals, 1946-1982; VI.
  - Freedom Press, 52.
  - Freedom Socialist Publications, 53.
  - Freedomways, 54.
  - Friends Committee on National Legislation, 55.
  - Friends General Conference, 56.
  - Friends of Free Asia, 57.
  - Friends of Michigan Schools, 58.
  - Friends of Rafferty, 59.
  - Friends of Reagan, 60.
  - Friends of Rhodesian Independence, 61.
  - Friends of the College Cevenol, 62.
  - Friends of the Schools News, 63.
  - Future, 64.
  - General Association of Regular Baptist Churches, 1. (Box 130)
  - Goethe, C. M., 2.
  - Goff, Oliver Kenneth, 3.
  - Gray, Al, 4.
  - Greater Nebraskan, 5.
  - Greek Report, 6.
  - Greystone Christian School, 7.
  - Group Research, Inc., 8.
  - Group Research, Inc. Directory, 9.
  - Grove Press, 10.
  - Gurney for Senate Committee, 11.
  - Hammer and Steel, 12.
  - Handgun Control, Inc., 13.
  - Harris County Friends of Senator Tower, 14.
  - Hawaii Foundation for American Freedom, 15.
  - Headlines, 16.
  - Heads Up, 17.
  - Herald of Freedom, 18.
  - Herald of Health, 19.
  - Heritage Schools, 20.
  - Heron House, 21.
  - Hilaire du Berrier Reports, 22.
  - Historical Commission of the United Church of Christ, 23.
  - Hope Publicity Bureau, 24.
  - Houston Tribune, 25.
  - Hudson, Charles B., 26.
  - Human Events, 27.
  - Humes, Ted, 28.
  - Huss for Congress Committee, 29.
  - Independence Foundation, 30.
  - Independent American, 31.
  - Independent Socialist Clubs of America, 32.
  - Individual's Manifesto, 33.
  - Industrial Worker, 34.
  - Information Council of the Americas, 35.
  - Innovator, 36.
  - Intelligence Digest, 37.
  - Intelligence International, 38.
  - Institute for American Democracy, 39.
  - Institute for Policy Studies Political Economy Program Center, 40.
  - Institute for the Study of Nonviolence, 41.
  - Inter-Church Holiness Convention, 42.
  - Intercollegiate Studies Institute, 43.
  - International Afro-American Museums, 44.
  - International Association of Amillenialists, 45.
  - International Association of Cancer Victims and Friends, 46.
  - International Catholic Truth Society, 47.
  - International Christian Relief, 48.
  - International Christian Youth, 49.
  - International Committee for the Defense of Christian Culture, 50.
  - International Council of Christian Churches, 51.
  - International Peasant Union, 52.
  - International Platform Association, 53.
  - International Publishers, 54.
  - Internationalist Perspective, 55.
  - Interpreter, 56.
  - Interracial Review, 57.
  - Israel Bulletin, 58.
  - Israel Christian Truth, 59.
  - Jackson, Andrew, 1. (Box 131)
  - Jackson, Donald L., 2.
  - Jag, 3.
  - James Madison Foundation, 4.
  - Jeanette Rankin Brigade, 5.
  - Jefferson-Lincoln Americans, 6.
  - Jewish Society of Americanists, 7.
  - John Birch Society (Allegheny County, Pa.), 8.
  - John Birch Society (U.S.), 9.
  - Joint Council for Repatriation, 10.
  - Joint Study Commission on Meeting Revolutionary Challenges to America, 11.
  - Journal of Black Poetry, 12.
  - Journal of Social Psychology International, 13.
  - Kansas Free Lance, 14.
  - Kaufman, Gerald, 15.
  - Kimmel, J. S., 16.
  - Kingdom Bible College, 17.
  - Kingdom Bible Institute, 18.
  - Kluckhohn, Frank L., 19.
  - Koinona Partners, 20.
  - Korean Cultural and Freedom Foundation, 21.
  - La Raza, 22.
  - Labor Educational Association, 23.
  - LADO, 24.
  - Laissez-Faire Books, 25.
  - Landmark Hour, 26.
  - Lane College, 27.
  - Latin American Bureau, 28.
  - Layman's Commission, 29.
  - Layman's Home Missionary Movement, 30.
  - League for Industrial Democracy, 31.
  - League for Peace and Justice in Palestine, 32.
  - LeRoy, Robert, 33.
  - Lewis-Bruce Report, 34.
  - Liberation, 35.
  - Liberation Book Store, 36.
  - Liberation News Service (New York, N.Y.), 37.
  - Libertarian Alliance, 38.
  - Libertarian Press, 39.
  - Liberty Amendment Committee (U.S.), 40.
  - Liberty Amendment Committee (Pa.), 41.
  - Liberty Bell Press, 42.
  - Liberty Lobby, 43.
  - Life Line, 44.
  - Liturgical Conference, 45.
  - Livernois Five Defense Committee, 46.
  - Louisiana Joint Legislative Committee on Un-American Activities, 47.
  - Lutheran Free Conference, 48.
  - Lutheran News, 49.
  - Lutheran Alert National, 50.
  - Lyons, Florence Fowler, 51.
  - MacArthur Freedom Association, 52.
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 53.
  - Mahanota College, 54.
  - Manion Forum, 55.
  - Marah, 56.
  - Marian Foundation, 57.
  - Mason, H. Norton, 58.
  - May Valley Corp., 59.
  - Mayday, 60.
  - McCarthy for President, 61.
  - McGovern, George, 62.
  - Merit Publishers, 63.
  - Metcalf for U. S. Senate Committee, 64.
  - Michigan Challenge, 65.
  - Midnight Cry, 66.
  - Midnight Cry Messenger, 67.
  - Militant, 68.
  - Militant Christian American, 69.
  - Ministry of Christ Church, 70.
  - Minneapolis Community Union Project, 71.
  - Minor's Lamp, 72.
  - Minority of One, 73.
  - Minutemen, 74.
  - Miss Kassel Says, 75.
  - Modern Age, 76.
  - Modern Utopian, 77.
  - Mobile Beacon, 78.
  - Monroeville Times-Express, 79.
  - Moorhead, William S., 80.
  - Movement for American Hemispherical Unity, 81.
  - Movement Speakers Bureau, 82.
  - Movimiento Unidad Revolucionario, 83.
  - NAACP, 1. (Box 132)
  - National Association of Christian Schools, 2.
  - National Association of Evangelicals, 3.
  - National Baptist Publishing Board, 4.
  - National Campaign Against East-West Trade, 5.
  - National Caucus of Labor Committees, 6.
  - National Christian Association, 7.
  - National Christian Church, 8.
  - National Chronicle, 9.
  - National Committee for a Confrontation with Congress, 10.
  - National Committee for an Effective Congress, 11.
  - National Committee for the Liberation of China, 12.
  - National Conference for New Politics, 13.
  - National Conference for New Politics (Chicago, Ill.: 1968), 14.
  - National Council of Negro Women, 15.
  - National Counter-Intelligence Corps Association, 16.
  - National Eagle, 17.
  - National Economic Council, 18.
  - National Education Program, 19.
  - National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 20.
  - National Guardian, 21.
  - National Gun Control Center, 22.
  - National Health Federation, 23.
  - National Holiness Association, 24.
  - National Information Center, 25.
  - National Institute for Law, Order, Justice, 26.
  - National Fluoridation News, 27.
  - National Mobilization Committee to End the War in Vietnam, 28.
  - National Negro Congress of Racial Pride, 29.
  - National Organizing Committee, 30.
  - National Party of America, 31.
  - National Reform Association, 32.
  - National Review, 33.
  - National Right to Work Committee, 34.
  - National Right to Work Committee Legal Defense Foundation, 35.
  - National Sharecroppers Fund, 36.
  - National Socialist White People's Party, 37.
  - National Socialist World, 38.
  - National Sojourners, 39.
  - National States Rights Party, 40.
  - National Student Committee for Victory in Vietnam, 41.
  - National Tax Reform Center, 42.
  - National Taxpayers Union, 43.
  - National Whig Party, 44.
  - National Wildlife Foundation, 45.
  - National Youth Alliance, 46.
  - Naylor Co., 47.
  - New America, 48.
  - New Christian Crusade Church, 49.
  - New Democratic Coalition of Pennsylvania, 50.
  - New England Committee for Nonviolent Action, 51.
  - New England Free Press, 52.
  - New England Rally for God, Family and Country, 53.
  - New Lafayette Theatre, 54.
  - New Mobilization Committee to End the War in Vietnam, 55.
  - New Outlook, 56.
  - New Patriot, 57.
  - New Politics, 58.
  - New Spirit of '76 Foundation, 59.
  - New University Conference, 60.
  - New World Review, 61.
  - New York Free Press, 62.
  - New York Students for a Democratic Society Labor Committee, 63.
  - Newby, J. Edwin, 64.
  - News and Letter, 65.
  - 1976 Committee, 66.
  - Nixon-Agnew TV Committee, 67.
  - Nixon for President Committee (1968), 68.
  - Nixon, Richard M., 69.
  - Noontide Press, 70.
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), 71.
  - Northwood Institute, 72.
  - Oakland Cooperative Association (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 73.
  - Ohio Information Committee, 74.
  - Old Time Gospel Hour, 75.
  - Omni Publications, 76.
  - Open Air Campaigners, 77.
  - Our Country, 78.
  - Outdoor World, 79.
  - Palestine Liberation Organization, 1. (Box 133)
  - Parliament House, 2.
  - Patrick Henry Press, 3.
  - Patriotic Education, 4.
  - Patriotic Party, 5.
  - Patriotic Preview, 6.
  - Patriotic Research Bureau, 7.
  - Peace Movement of Ethiopia, 8.
  - Pendle Hill, 9.
  - Peninsula Observers, 10.
  - Pennsylvania Conservative Party, 11.
  - Pennsylvania Conservative Union, 12.
  - Pennsylvania Constitution Party, 13.
  - Pennsylvania Right to Work Defense and Education Fund, 14.
  - Pennsylvanians for the Right to Work, 15.
  - Pentagon Papers Fund, 16.
  - People for the American Way, 17.
  - People's Fund, 18.
  - People's World, 19.
  - Philadelphia Society, 20.
  - Pittsburgh Coalition for Disarmament and Social Justice, 21.
  - Pittsburgh Council on Public Education, 22.
  - Pittsburgh Veterans for Peace, 23.
  - Pittsburgh Student Coalition Against Racism, 24.
  - Planned Dynamic Progress International, 25.
  - Plano University, 26.
  - Police Hall of Fame, 27.
  - Political Affairs, 28.
  - Poor People's Campaign, 29.
  - Power Products, 30.
  - Presbyterian Lay Committee, 31.
  - Prevention, 32.
  - Prism, 33.
  - Progressive Labor Party, 34.
  - Progressive National Baptist Convention, 35.
  - Prophetic Herald, 36.
  - Prophetic Reporter Publications, 37.
  - Public Action, 38.
  - Public Trust Foundation, 39.
  - Pure Water Association of America, 40.
  - Quaker Action Group, 41.
  - Race, 42.
  - Radical Education Project, 43.
  - Radical Organizing Committee, 44.
  - Radio Church of God, 45.
  - Radio Free Asia, 46.
  - Rafferty, Max, 47.
  - Rally Magazine, 48.
  - Rampart College, 49.
  - Ramparts Magazine, 50.
  - Rarick, John, 51.
  - Reagan, Ronald, 52.
  - Reality Evangelism, 53.
  - Reason, 54.
  - Rebellion News, 55.
  - Regular Baptist Press, 56.
  - Religious Society of Friends, 57.
  - Religious Society of Friends Lake Erie Yearly Meeting, 58.
  - Remnant, 59.
  - Republic of China Embassy, 60.
  - Republic of New Africa, 61.
  - Republican National Committee, 62.
  - Republican Party, 63.
  - Republicans, Independents and Democrats United, 64.
  - Resist, 65.
  - Revolutionary Socialist Students Federation, 66.
  - Richard Walker Reports, 67.
  - Right Start for the Day, 68.
  - Roberts, Arch E., 69.
  - Safe Return, 70.
  - St. Michael's Norbertine Seminary, 71.
  - St. Thomas Press, 72.
  - Sam Adams Committee of Public Safety, 73.
  - San Diego Patriotic Society, 74.
  - Sandtown Story, 75.
  - Sane, 76.
  - Save Our Nation, 77.
  - Schlafly, Fred and Phyllis, 78.
  - Schmitz, John G., 79.
  - Schweiker, Dick, 80.
  - Scott, Hugh, 81.
  - Sexual Freedom League, 82.
  - Shambaugh Families News Letter, 83.
  - Shearon Legislative Service, 84.
  - Situationist International, 85.
  - Skinner, Floyd L., 86.
  - Slovak League of America, 87.
  - Social Welfare History Group, 88.
  - Social Workers Union (Oakland, Calif.), 89.
  - Socialist Labor Party (Allegheny County, Pa.), 90.
  - Socialist Labor Party (Pa.), 91.
  - Socialist Labor Party (U.S.), 92.
  - Socialist Party U.S.A., 93.
  - Socialist Workers Party, 94.
  - Society for Rational Individualism, 95.
  - Society for the Christian Commonwealth, 96.
  - Soldiers of the Cross, 1. (Box 134)
  - Solidarity Publications, 2.
  - Sons of Liberty, 3.
  - Sons of the American Revolution (California Society), 4.
  - South Louisiana Citizens Council, 5.
  - Southern Christian Leadership Conference, 6.
  - Southern Conference Education Fund, 7.
  - Southern Conservative, 8.
  - Southern Methodist Church, 9.
  - Southern Review, 10.
  - Space City News, 11.
  - Spark, 12.
  - Spartacist, 13.
  - Spirit of '76 House, 14.
  - Spotlight, 15.
  - Stacey, David K., 16.
  - Statecraft, 17.
  - Stephen Decatur Society, 18.
  - Stop ERA, 19.
  - Student Committee for a Free China, 20.
  - Student Committee for a Victory in Vietnam, 21.
  - Student Mobilization Committee, 22.
  - Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee, 23.
  - Students for a Democratic Society, 24.
  - Students to Oppose Participation in the National Student Association, 25.
  - Summit Lighthouse, 26.
  - Supreme Court Amendment League, 27.
  - Swarthmore College, 28.
  - Sword of the Lord, 29.
  - Tactics, 30.
  - Task Force on the Panama Canal, 31.
  - Taxpayers Action, 32.
  - Taxpayers Educational Association, 33.
  - Technocracy, 34.
  - Teenage Republicans, 35.
  - Texas Observer, 36.
  - Thomas A. Dooley Foundation, 37.
  - Times of the Americas, 38.
  - Tocsin, 39.
  - Tower, John, 40.
  - Tri-Continental Information Center, 41.
  - Tri-State Informer, 42.
  - Triumph, 43.
  - True News, 44.
  - Trumpet Press, 45.
  - Truth About Communism, 46.
  - Truth About Cuba Committee, 47.
  - Truth and Liberty Magazine, 48.
  - Truth Crusader, 49.
  - Truth Seeker, 50.
  - Tuskeegee Institute, 51.
  - Twin Circle Publishing Co., 52.
  - Twin Oaks Community, 53.
  - Ukrainian Bulletin, 54.
  - Ukrainian Congress Committee of America, 55.
  - Una Voce, 56.
  - Uncommon Sense, 57.
  - Union of Vietnamese Students in France, 58.
  - United Congressional Appeal, 59.
  - United Farm Workers Organizing Committee (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 60.
  - United Farm Workers of America, 61.
  - United Nations Association of the U.S.A., 62.
  - United Republicans of America, 63.
  - United Republicans of Pennsylvania, 64.
  - United Resistance Fund, 65.
  - United States Ant-Communist Congress, 66.
  - United States Bureau of the Census, 67.
  - United States Committee to Aid the National Liberation Front of South Vietnam, 68.
  - United States Committee for Justice to Latin American Political Prisoners, 69.
  - United States Day Committee, 70.
  - United States Farmers Association, 71.
  - United States Flag Committee, 72.
  - United States Government Printing Office, 73.
  - United Steelworkers of America, 74.
  - United World Federalists, 75.
  - Universal Challenger, 76.
  - USA, 77.
  - Utt, James B., 78.
  - Veterans for Peace in Vietnam, 1. (Box 135)
  - Victory in Vietnam Banquet Committee, 2.
  - Vietnam GI, 3.
  - Vietnam Summer, 4.
  - Vietnam Veterans Against the War, 5.
  - View From Here, 6.
  - Viewpoint Books, 7.
  - Voice of Americanism, 8.
  - Voice of Liberty, 9.
  - Voice of the Federation, 10.
  - Voice of the Nazarene Association of Churches, 11.
  - Voice of Truth, 12.
  - Voice of Truth and Freedom, 13.
  - Volunteers for Wallace, 14.
  - WGCB (Radio Station), 15.
  - Wallace Campaign (1976), 16.
  - Wanderer, 17.
  - Wanderer Forum, 18.
  - War/Peace Report, 19.
  - Washington Observer, 20.
  - Washington Peace Center, 21.
  - War Resisters League, 22.
  - Wayne, John, 23.
  - We The People, 24.
  - Weekly Vigil for Peace, 25.
  - Western Destiny, 26.
  - Western Front, 27.
  - Western Messenger, 28.
  - Western Pennsylvania Conservancy, 29.
  - Western Unity Research Center, 30.
  - Western Voice, 31.
  - Western World Review, 32.
  - White Americans to Support Black Liberation, 33.
  - White Equal Rights Party (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 34.
  - White Star, 35.
  - Wider Quaker Fellowship, 36.
  - Wilderness Society, 37.
  - William Penn House, 38.
  - Wilkinsburg Sentinel, 39.
  - Williamson's Political Highlights, 40.
  - Willis E. Stone for President, 41.
  - Win, 42.
  - Wings of Healing, 43.
  - Winrod, Gerald B., 44.
  - Winrod, Gordon, 45.
  - Wisconsin Draft Resistance Union, 46.
  - Wisconsin Evangelical Lutheran Synod, 47.
  - Woman's Right to Know, 48.
  - Women for Constitutional Government, 49.
  - Women's Voice, 50.
  - Workers League, 51.
  - Workers World, 52.
  - Working People's Party of England, 53.
  - World Baptist Fellowship, 54.
  - World Evangelism, 55.
  - World Presbyterian Missions, 56.
  - World Prophetic Ministry, 57.
  - World Revolutions, 58.
  - World Wildlife Fund, 59.
  - World Youth Crusade for Freedom, 60.
  - Yippies, 61.
  - Young Americans for Freedom, 62.
  - Young Friends of North America, 63.
  - Young People's Socialist League, 64.
  - Young Socialist Alliance, 65.
  - Youth Against World Fascism, 66.
  - Youth for Christ International, 67.
  - Youth for Stalin, 68.
  - Youth for Voluntary Prayer Amendment, 69.
  - Youth for Wallace, 70.
- Subject Files, 1946-1982; VII.
  This series consists of files on several topics related to both the far right and the far left. It contains newspaper clippings, correspondence, fliers and other types of materials, arranged alpabetically by subject.
  - Anti-Radical Right Materials, 1. (Box 136)
  - Directories, Catalogs and Bibliographies, 2.
  - Pittsburgh (Pa.), 3.
  - Presidential Campaign of 1964 and the Radical Right, 4.
  - Radical Left, 5.
  - Radical Right, 6.
  - Radical Right in Pennsylvania, 7.
  - Radical Right in Pittsburgh (Pa.), 8.
  - Religious Materials, 9.
  - Republican Party and the Radical Right, 10.
  - Vietnam, 11.
  - Vietnam War, 12.